Clinton Unegbu

unegbuclinton5@gmail.com 08030905388 25 Ayodele Street Oshodi, Lagos

Summary

Diligent professional with 3 years of work experience and a proven knowledge of advanced technology, and passion for responsive website design and a firm believer in the mobile-first approach. Eager to tackle problems and continuously finding ways to maximize user efficiency.

Experience

Front End Developer

Biggorillaapps Remote

02/2022 - Present

- Designed and maintain inhouse data analytic web application using Node.js & Express.Js for the server side application, MongoDB for the database, EJS & Bootstrap for the layouts increasing company sales revenue.
- Joined a cross functional team to complete a gamified crypto currency exchange application using react and tailwind for component styling.
- Spearheaded a team of frontend engineers to build and implement a fintech project, consuming REST API using React.is, styled component for the component styling and Redux Toolkit for the state management.
- Developed dynamic wordpress template using HTML5, CSS3 and javascript.
- Review codes and Merge codes.

Frontend Developer

Fiverr Remote

09/2021 - 07/2022

- Transform app designs into front-end code with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Gather and refine specifications and requirements based on technical requirements or UX design
- Refactor web application for performance optimization

Growth Engineering Intern

Curacel Remote

03/2020 - 04/2021

- Build Landing Page for online campaigns and track pages
- Increased their online followers to 60% in three months
- create interactive contents that speak the brand's language and convert leads.

Frontend developer Intern

Zuri Internship Programme Remote

04/2019 - 08/2019

- Collaborate with back-end developers and web designers to build responsive web application using react and css predecessors.
- Peer programming with teammates to translate UI designs to pixel perfect web applications using frontend technologies.
- Brainstorm session with team for better technical solutions
- Implement enhancement that improved web functionality and responsiveness
- Learned new modern frontend technologies like Redux state management tool, styled-component, Axios

Skills:

React.js,NextJs, JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, Express, MongoD, Styled-component, Tailwind css, Redux toolkit, Version Control(Git), Figma

Education:

Business Administration University of Nigeria Enugu

Languages

English